[Music]
i am passionate about
finding ways to connect with the natural
world
and recently i've been experimenting
with natural
dyes
[Music]
the most important part of this process
is choosing your fabric
you must choose a natural fabric such as
linen or cotton
i've left some details in the
description bar
i'm not a seamstress in any sense of the
term but
i wanted to make a simple apron that i
could use around the house and in the
garden
i was planning to wash my apron quite
often
and i didn't expect any natural dye to
actually permanently adhere to the
fabric
if you want your dye to last and not
fade or wash out completely over time
you must use a piece of clothing or
fabric that you don't plan to be
throwing into the wash
every week
[Music]
i was in no particular need for new
clothing so i decided to
make the linen into strips for use as
headbands
and future craft projects such as
lavender sachets
[Music]
do
so
[Music]
you should leave the fabric in its dye
bath for about 24 hours or more
i was very impatient and only looking
for a light wash of color
so i checked back after only about 12
[Music]
hours
do
[Music]
the blue cabbage dye left my apron a
stunning shade of purple
even though i was planning to wash out
the garment multiple times in the future
i was very happy with the initial result
[Music]
as you can see the colors and shades you
can get from just these few vegetables i
used are
pretty much endless and there's so many
more options available
i encourage you to experiment and find
new methods that work for you i've left
some
resources down below
if you enjoyed this video consider
subscribing i make new ones every
wednesday in the meantime i hope you
have a lovely day
and i will see you next week